Guide to the A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust Records, 1930-1980 AIS.1980.29
ULS Archives & Special Collections
A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust Records
1930-1980
ULS Archives & Special Collections
A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust
AIS.1980.29
72.5 Linear Feet (60 boxes)
The A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust operated as a financial supporter of the arts, culture, and education from 1930 to 1980. The collection documents the internal business operations of the Trust and its relation with the organizations, institutions, and programs that it funded.
History
The A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust, founded by Andrew W. Mellon in 1930, contributed funding to a variety of organizations, insitutions, and programs until it dissolved in 1980. In its fifty year life the Trust made nearly $200,000,000 in contributions, including over $25,000,000 in termination grants at the time of its dissolution in 1980.
On the national level, the A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust provided funding and support to The National Gallery of Art, initially created largely through the donation of Andrew Mellon's private art collection. The Trust made major donations for construction of the Gallery Building in Washington, D.C. In addition, the Trust also contributed funding to the Smithsonian Institute, Atlantic Council of the United States, as well as other national and international organizations.
The Trust played an important role in the funding of the arts and culture life in Pittsburgh. The Carnegie Museum's International Exhibitions were renewed after the Second World War, in large part due to the Trust's role as underwriter from 1959-1980. The Carnegie Institute also a benefitted from the Trust. Gifts helped fund the Three Rivers Arts Festival, the 1972 Pittsburgh Jazz Festival, creation of the Selma Burke Art Center, and three archeological expeditions for the Carnegie Museum of Natural History.
In the field of education gifts from the Trust in 1949, the Trust helped establish the Graduate School of Public Health at the University of Pittsburgh. This gift became the focal point of the University's attempt to lift Pitt to national stature during the 1950's. In addition, the University of Pittsburgh, Carnegie Mellon University, and Chatham College all benefited from gifts of endowed faculty chairs and grants for specific programs. According to its final report, the Trust had given nearly $72 million dollars to these educational programs during its lifetime.
Other local organizations that benefited from the Trust's financial support included Allegheny Conference on Community Development, Action Housing, Pittsburgh Regional Planning Association, and Pennsylvania Economy League. It also helped establish the Western Pennsylvania Conservancy in 1951, with the building of Mellon Square Park in downtown Pittsburgh and in acquiring six parks for the Allegheny County Parks System. In 1954, in partnership with the Ford Foundation, the Trust helped launch the Metropolitan Pittsburgh Educational Television Station, later to become WQED.
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust cover the organization's operations from its beginning in 1930 to the time of its liquidation in 1980. In the collection, researchers will find both internal business records and records dealing with the organizations, institutions, and programs funded by the trust.
Internal Business records can be found in Series I. -- Business Records, 1930-1979, Series IV. -- Foundation Reports, 1930-1979, and Series V. -- Miscellaneous Records. Material in the files include minute books, cash books, meeting agendas, reports, investments, financial statements, and correspondence.
Researchers looking at organizations who received funding from the Trust may be especially interested in the Foundation Reports (Series IV.). Organizations in these reports include the Smithsonian Institution, National Gallery of Art, Avalon Foundation, Bolligen Foundation, Old Dominion Foundation, Mellon Institute, and Post-Doctoral Fellowship Program at the University of Pittsburgh. Also included in these files are records documenting the dissolution and liquidation of the Trust.
The bulk of records dealing with Trust contibutions can be found in:
Series VI -- Current Contributions, 1970-1980, Series VII -- Back Contributions, and Series XIV-- Contibutions, 1930-1970. Related records can also be found in Series VIII -- General Back Years, Series XI -- Cultural, Series XII -- Education, and Series XIII -- Miscellaneous Patman and Mellon Material.
Organizations, institutions, and programs covered in the files are numerous and include the University of Pittsburgh, Carnegie Mellon University (including both Carnegie Tech and Mellon Institute), Chatham College, the Carnegie Institute, National Gallery of Art, Smithsonian Institution, Atlantic Council of the Unites States, Arts Society of Pittsbrugh (as well as numerous other local cultural organizations), WQED, and Western Pennsylvania Conservancy. For a complete list of organizations researchers may want to consult the card index in box 12.
Also of interest to researchers may be the files dealing with funding declinations in Series X.
Other Series in the collection includes files concerning the Mellon Estate (Series XV), the Mellon Family (Series XVII), the Orphans Court (Series XVI), Trust policies, and program materials (Series XIX and XXII).
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Acquired from the A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust in 1980, as part of its liquidation.
Previous Citation
A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust Records, 1930-1980, AIS.1980.29, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Charities -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Pennsylvania; Education; Associations; A.W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust
- Business Records, 1930-1979; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains materials related to internal operations of the Trust. These include: minute books, cash books, records of contribution, meeting agendas, background on various organizations, reports, and other documentation
  - Minute Books, v. 1-7, December 30, 1930-September 25, 1947 (Box 1, Volume 1-7)
  - Minute Books, v. 8-14, October 6, 1947-November 10, 1975 (Box 2, Volume 8-14)
  - Cash Book, 1930-1970 (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - Journal/Cash Book, v.1, 1930-1943 (Box 3, Volume 2)
  - Journal/Cash Book, v.2, 1943-1952 (Box 3, Volume 3)
  - Record of Contributions, v.1, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Volume 4)
  - Record of Contributions, v.2, 1954-1959 (Box 3, Volume 5)
  - Agenda: Meetings of the Board of Trustees and of the Executive Committee, October, 1964-October, 1974 (Box 4, Volume 1-25)
  - Agendas: Meetings of the Board of Trustees and of the Executive Committee, March, 1975-November, 1979 (Box 5, Volume 1-16)
  - Background materials for termination grants, December, 1978 (Box 5, Volume 17)
  - Resumes of cultural organizations, Pittsburgh, March, 1978 (Box 5, Volume 18)
  - Carnegie Mellon University, Restoration of College of Fine Arts Project (Box 5, Volume 19)
  - Final report of Carnegie Mellon University College of Fine Arts Restoration Project, 1975 (Box 5, Volume 20)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, "Financial Support for the Fine Arts", October, 1957 (Box 5, Volume 21)
  - Pittsburgh Council for the Arts, 1968 (Box 5, Volume 22)
  - Information for Prospective Contributors on the Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, Inc, 1977 (Box 5, Volume 23)
  - Samuel Hazo and Theodore Hazlett trip to Sweden for poetry award, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence re: R.C. Alberts book "The Shaping of the World", 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Pittsburgh Jazz Festival, Clippings and Photo Album, 1972 (Box 6, Volume 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting with Scudder, Stevens, Scudder Re: Portfolio of the Trust, 1965-1979 (Box 6, Volume 2)
  - Report on Andrew Mellon Professors, Postdcotoral Fellows, Predoctoral Fellows, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Volume 3-4)
  - The Arts in Pittsburgh -- Common Place Book, 1978 (Box 6, Volume 5)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, "A Presentation of the Fine Arts Project at CIT Prepared for the A.W. Mellon Education and Charitable Trust", 1968 (Box 6, Volume 6-12)
  - Memorial Booklet to Carter Goodrich, Mellon Professor of Economics at the University of Pittsburgh, 1971 (Box 6, Volume 13)
  - Office furnishings and equipment (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - American Security and Trust Co., Washington, D.C. (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
  - Transfer and sale of Gulf Oil Corporation Stock, 1942-1963 (Box 7, Folder 5-12)
  - Liquidation of the Trust, March 31, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
- Dr. R.A. McConnell -- Research in Psychological Physics, 1930-1979; II.
  - The Works of R.A. McConnell in the field of parapsychology, 1950-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Psychological Physics Research Project, 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1953-1969 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Financial records, 1952-1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Extra copies, clippings, etc., 1951-1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - University of Pittsburgh Psychological Physics Program, 1974-1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Selma Burke Art Center, III.
  - Selma Burke Art Center (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
- Foundation Reports, 1930-1979; IV.
  Contains reports relating to several national organizations including: Smithsonian Institution, National Gallery of Art, Avalon Foundation, Bolligen Foundation, and Old Dominion Foundation. Also included are reports regarding the Mellon Institute and the Post-Doctoral Fellowship Program at the University of Pittsburgh.
  - A.W. Mellon Education and Charitable Trust Report and Deed of Trust, 1930-1979 (Box 10, Volume 1)
  - Old Dominion Foundation, 1941-1968 (Box 10, Volume 2)
  - The Andrew Mellon Foundation, 1969-1978 (Box 10, Volume 3)
  - Bolligen Foundation, 1945-1967 (Box 10, Volume 4)
  - Report of the Avalon Foundation, 1940-1968 (Box 10, Volume 5)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1878-1972 (Box 10, Volume 6-10)
  - National Gallery of Art, 1938-1975 (Box 10, Volume 10-18)
  - The Arts at the Conference of Mayor, June 9-13, 1979 (Box 10, Volume 19)
  - Richard King Mellon Foundation Annual Report, 1974 (Box 10, Volume 20)
  - Mellon Institute Annual Report, 1979 (Box 10, Volume 21)
  - Scholars for the Future: An Assessment of the Andrew Mellon Post-Doctoral Fellowship Program at the University of Pittsburgh, 1960-1976 (Box 10, Volume 22)
- Trust Records, V.
  - Cash Book, Pittsburgh and Washington Offices, 1930-1980 (Box 11, Volume 1-2)
  - Two 3x5 metal boxes, Card File Indexes and Files Index (Box 12)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, January 24, 1950-March25, 1963 (Box 13, Volume 1)
  - Gulf Oil Corporation 1,670,000 shares. Closed, June 27, 1961 (Box 13, Volume 2)
  - General Financial Ledger, 1959-1970 (Box 13, Volume 3)
  - Record of Contributions, 1949-1954 (Box 13, Volume 4)
  - Graduate School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh, Paul Mellon's Dedication Speech (Box 13, Volume 5-6)
  - Mt. Washington Duquense Heights, "A Study for the Department of Parks and Recreation, July 1970 (Box 13, Volume 7)
  - "The Mellons of Pittsburgh" from Fortune Magazine, 1967 (Box 13, Volume 8-9)
  - Procedure Manual (Box 13, Volume 10)
  - The Allegheny Conference on Community Development Presents Pittsburgh and Allegheny County An Era Of Progress and Accomplishment, 1956 (Box 13, Volume 11)
  - Cash Book (Box 14, Volume 1)
  - Security Record (Box 15, Volume 1)
  - Cash Book -- Financial Statements, 1930-1969 (Box 16, Volume 1)
  - American Symphony Orchestra League Golden Baton Award to Paul Mellon, 1984 (Box 17, Othertype 1)
  - Scrapbook -- Mellon Endowment to Carnegie Institute of Technology, December 1958 (Box 17, Volume 2)
  - Wooden Cabinet containing 3"x5" File Indedx Prior to, 1971 (Box 18)
- Current Contributions, 1970-1980; VI.
  - Metropolitan Opera (Pittsburgh District Visitors) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - The Opera Workshop, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Pittsburgh Council for International Visitors (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Grants (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Action Housing, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 5-7)
  - Allegheny Conference (Box 19, Folder 8-11)
  - American Waterways (Box 19, Folder 12-14)
  - American Wind Symphony (Box 19, Folder 15-19)
  - Arts and Crafts (Box 19, Folder 20-22)
  - Associated Artists (Box 19, Folder 23-25)
  - Associated Councils of the Arts (Box 19, Folder 26-28)
  - Atlantic Council of the U.S., Inc (Box 19, Folder 29-31)
  - Bach Choir (Box 19, Folder 32-34)
  - Buhl Planetarium (Box 19, Folder 35-37)
  - Carnegie Institute (Box 19, Folder 38-41)
  - Carnegie Institute, Children's Museum (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Carnegie Institute, International (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Carnegie Institute, Report on the Pittsburgh International Exhibition of Contemperary Art (Box 19, Folder 44-47)
  - Carnegie Institute, Creatadrama (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Institute, Film Makers (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Institute, The First Stage (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Institute, Sculpture Program (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Institute, Burke Center (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
  - Carnegie Institute, Three Rivers Art Festival (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Library, Poetry Dance (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Library, A.W. Mellon International Collection -- Poetry (Box 20, Folder 9-11)
  - Carnegie Library, MacLeish Project (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Library, Mundus Atrium (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Carnegie Library, Ralph Munn Creative Writer's Program (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University, Scholarships, teaching training, National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students (NSSFNS) (Box 20, Folder 15-17)
  - Chatham College, library endowment, central research, National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro students (NSSFNS) (Box 20, Folder 18-20)
  - City of Pittsburgh, North Side Library (Box 20, Folder 21-23)
  - Civic Light Opera (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - County of Allegheny (Box 21, Folder 4-6)
  - Dusquesne University (Box 21, Folder 7-10)
  - Episcopal Diocese of Pittsburgh (Box 21, Folder 11-13)
  - Fort Pitt Museum Association, Inc. (Box 21, Folder 14-16)
  - Gateway to Music (Box 21, Folder 17-19)
  - Handweavers Guild (Box 21, Folder 20-22)
  - Historical Society (Box 21, Folder 23-25)
  - Iron Clad Agreement (Box 21, Folder 26-28)
  - Junior League (Box 21, Folder 29-31)
  - Manchester Craftsmen's Guild (Box 21, Folder 32-34)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council, Inc. (Box 21, Folder 35-36)
  - Mendolssohn Choir (Box 21, Folder 37-39)
  - Metropolitan Broadcasting (Box 21, Folder 40-44)
  - National Endowment (Box 21, Folder 45-47)
  - National Gallery of Art (Box 22, Folder 1-3)
  - National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students (NSSFNS) (Box 22, Folder 4-6)
  - Negro Educational Emergency Drive (Box 22, Folder 7-9)
  - Pennsylvania Ballet (Box 22, Folder 10-12)
  - Pittsburgh, Ballet Theatre (Box 22, Folder 13-15)
  - Pittsburgh, Chamber Music Society (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Pittsburgh, Communication Foundation (Box 22, Folder 17-19)
  - Pittsburgh, Council for the Arts (Box 22, Folder 20-22)
  - Pittsburgh, Dance Council (Box 22, Folder 23-25)
  - Pittsburgh, Drama League (Box 22, Folder 26-28)
  - Pittsburgh, Film-Makers Association (Box 22, Folder 29-32)
  - Pittsburgh, Foundation (Box 22, Folder 33-35)
  - Pittsburgh, Laboratory Theatre (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
  - Pittsburgh, Opera (Box 23, Folder 4-6)
  - Pittsburgh, Oratorio Society (Box 23, Folder 7-9)
  - Pittsburgh, Plan for Art (Box 23, Folder 10-12)
  - Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater (Box 23, Folder 13-15)
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools, Urban Plan (Box 23, Folder 16-17)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater Corporation (Box 23, Folder 18-20)
  - Pittsburgh, Symphony Society (Box 23, Folder 21-24)
  - Pittsburgh, Youth Symphony Orchestra (Box 23, Folder 25-27)
  - Pittsburgh, History and Landmarks Foundation (Box 23, Folder 36-38)
  - Point Park College (Box 23, Folder 28-30)
  - Renaissance and Baroque Society (Box 23, Folder 31-33)
  - Robert Morris College (Box 23, Folder 34-36)
  - Schizophrenia Foundation of New Jersey (Box 23, Folder 37-39)
  - Theatre Express (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
  - Three Rivers Orchestra Association (Box 24, Folder 4-6)
  - Vanguard Theatre (Box 24, Folder 7-9)
  - University of Pittsburgh (Box 24, Folder 10-15)
  - Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association (Box 24, Folder 17-19)
  - Western Pennsylvania Conservancy (Box 24, Folder 20-24)
  - Agenda (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Annual Reports, 1970-1977 (Box 24, Folder 26-33)
  - Art Works, Neal Harold (Box 24, Folder 34-36)
  - Assets (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - By-Laws (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Consultants (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Contributions (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Trustee Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Council of Foundations (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Employment (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Foundations (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Hazlett, Theodore (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Mellon Family (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Minutes Current (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Office Equipment and Furnishings (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Philanthropy (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Purchase Declinations (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Questionnaires (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Reporting Services (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Secretary Trust (Box 25, Folder 16)
- Back Contributions, VII.
  - Allegheny Conference of Community Development (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Arts and Crafts Center (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Atlantic Council of the U.S., Inc. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Bach Choir (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Carnegie Institute, Ashdod Excavation (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Carnegie Institute, Creatadrama (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Museum, International Art Show (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Institute, Jazz Festival (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Institute, Three Rivers Art Festival (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Institute, International Exhibition (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Library, International Poetry Forum (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Mellon, Music Extension Program (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Mellon, College of Fine Arts (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Mellon, National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Chatham College (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Chatham College, Library Support (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Chatham College, National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Chatham College, Select Commission on the Pittsburgh School Board (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Civic Light Opera Association (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Clef Concert Association of Greater Pittsburgh, Inc. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Commonwealth Cultural Foundation (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - The Harriet Tubman Guild, Inc. (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - The Hugh Moore Foundation (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - The Mendelssohn Choir (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Metropolitan Pittsburgh Educational Television -- WQED (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - National Gallery of Art, Pittsburgh Public Schools Art Project (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Negro Educational Emergency Drive (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Pittsburgh, History and Landmarks Foundation (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Pittsburgh, Plan for Art, Pittsburgh Dance Council (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Pittsburgh, Playhouse (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Pittsburgh, Public Schools (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Pittsburgh, Symphony Society (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh, Theological Seminary (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Planning Foundation of America (American Institute of Planners) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Pocono Art Center (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Point Park College (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Robert Morris College, African Heritage Association Inc. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Mary Church (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Southwestern Regional Planning Comission (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Theta Sigma Phi (Writers Conference) (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Center for International Studies, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Policy Research Institute, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Graduate School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Library, Hayden Exhibition, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - International Information Center for the Arts, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - International Library Information Center, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Andrew Mellon Professorship and Fellowship Program, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 17-20)
  - Mellon Student Art Study, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Contributions, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Chapter of the American Society for Public Administration, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Council for International Visitors, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Negro Scholarship Program, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Press, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 26-27)
  - Western Psychiatric Institute, University of Pittsburgh (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Urban Redevelopment Authority (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Vanguard Theater Project (Box 27, Folder 30)
- General Back Years, VIII.
  - Agenda Back Years (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Contribution Lists (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - List of Contribution Declinations (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 6-8)
- Trusts A-Z, IX.
  - Miscellaneous A-Z (Box 28, Folder 9-40)
- Declinations, X.
  - Applications not granted (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - List of contributions and declinations (transfer file) (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - American Organizations, A-F (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - American Organizations, G-Z (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - A-D (Box 28, Folder 45-48)
  - E-U (Box 29, Folder 1-21)
  - University-Z (Box 30, Folder 1-4)
- Cultural, XI.
  - Affiliate Artists Inc. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - American Wind Symphony (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Art Centers (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Art Galleries (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Artistic Workshop, Selma Burke (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Artists and Craftsmen Guild, Inc. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Arts and Crafts Center (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Arts and Education (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Arts Information International (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Arts and Craft Center (capital) (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Associated Artists of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh for Art (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Atlantic Institute for International Affairs (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Institute, Filmakers (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Institute (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Three Rivers Arts Festival (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Library (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Film Makers (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - North Side Carnegie Library Rehabilitation, Vanguard (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Civic Light Opera, Financial (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - The Clef Concert Association of Pittsburgh, Inc. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Cultural Organization of Greater Pittsburgh (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Dance (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Duquesne University Tamburitzans, Inc. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - The First Stage (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Floating Center for the Arts (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Frick Art Musuem (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Heinz Hall for the Performing Arts (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Institute in Arts Administration (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - International University Choral Festival (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - The Junior League of Pittsburgh, Inc. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Marionette Theatre Arts Council, Inc. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - The Mendelssohn Choir (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - National Gallery of Art (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania Ballet (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh, Chamber Music Society, Inc. (Box 32, Folder 7)